Amen.
Good morning.
My mic on?
Dave, I know I'm hot, but is my mic on?
We're full of unscripted jokes today.
Can you hear me?
Dave says keep, or Doc says keep rolling, so I'm going to keep rolling there.
It's starting to come in.
Perfect, perfect, perfect.
All right, well, good morning, everyone.
Thank you all for joining us this morning.
My name is Ryan.
If we haven't met yet, I have the privilege of being one of the pastors here.
And as you can tell, we are continuing our series on the parables.
This is week three of the parables of Jesus.
And I just want to remind you that one of our core values as a church is that we rely on the written and living word of God.
So we are a people of the Scriptures.
We are a people of the Scriptures who believe that the Scriptures were given to us to reveal Jesus to us.
That John says he, in the beginning was the word, and the word became flesh and dwelt among us.
That all of the Scriptures are intended to point us to Jesus.
And so when Jesus talks, we want to pay close attention to it.
And parables are a significant part of Jesus' teaching, of Jesus' talking.
Depending on how you categorize the parables, people think there are 30 to 40 parables in the Gospels.
And one-third, one-third of the red letters that you will find in the Gospels are parables.
Now, because of that fact, we cannot cover them all because it would be a two-year-long series.
And we all know that you guys' attention span is not that good.
Nor is mine.
So I will put the judgment on myself there.
But my goal is to cover a few different types of parables
and kind of help you understand how I am doing my best,
how we as communicators on the stage are interpreting the parables
so that you have the tools to read the parables for yourself,
to interpret them for yourself.
And Kent opened up the series by saying that parables are indirect communication
aimed at challenging previously held assumptions.
They're a way in which Jesus is able to get through the back window of our imagination, of our hearts.
They appeal to our imagination.
Most of us, by the time we get to a certain age, have concrete ideas about what we believe.
And the same was true for Jesus' audience.
They had concrete ideas specifically about what they believed the kingdom of heaven
and the kingdom of God was like.
And Jesus came saying the kingdom of heaven is something totally different
than what you are thinking it is like.
And they struggled with that.
And so he told these stories to try and help engage their imagination
so that they didn't just shut down from what he was saying,
but they were able to walk away from his teaching and marinate on it and think about it.
In context, when we read the parables, we first need to understand what Jesus is saying to his original audience.
The church has a habit of reading the parables as if they were written directly to us,
as if Jesus is speaking past his audience to a future audience.
And the reality is that's not the case.
He was speaking to the group of people that were in front of him.
Now, they were recorded for us and have significance for us.
But in order for us to understand them properly, we have to understand Jesus' intent first.
One scholar I really like says that there's a difference between intention and significance.
So the intention is what Jesus was trying to communicate to his audience.
And the significance is then how do we understand what he was intending to say to his audience?
How does that apply to us?
What does that mean for our lives?
As I was prepping for this series, I was trying to find a neat, clean, organized way that scholars agree on characterizing the parables.
Still looking?
Yeah.
Yeah, I found at least 50 different ways that different scholars categorize the parables.
And so I ended up settling on this one categorization because it's only three categories.
And we all know three is better than seven or 11, which some of the other ones had.
So the three categories that we're going to work through for the rest of the series are the surprising parables about the surprising arrival of God's kingdom,
the surprising ethic of God's kingdom.
And then as we get closer to Jerusalem, as the temperature is rising around Jesus and his teaching,
his parables get significantly more pointed and challenging.
And those are parables of crisis of choice.
He's putting the arrival and the ethic of the kingdom in front of his audience.
And he's saying, there's about to come a time where you're going to have to choose which of these kingdoms you're going to live for.
So last week and this week is going to be the arrival.
We'll move to the ethic next week and we'll end with choice.
But I just wanted to give you a framework so you knew that I did have a plan and an intention behind the series.
Sound good?
All right.
With all that, yeah, let's go.
Rachel's ready.
She's like, enough of this.
Let's get started.
All right.
With all that recap and context, let's pray and dive into our two parables today.
They are the shortest of the parables, relatively easy to understand intellectually, but extremely challenging for our lives.
So let's pray.
Father in heaven, Abba.
We thank you for Jesus.
We thank you for the Scriptures that, from Genesis all the way through Revelation, point us to Jesus, the ultimate fulfillment of your purposes and your plan to redeem this broken world.
To bring it back to rights, to reconcile it to its good design.
God, right now we experience so much brokenness, so much pain, so much heartache, so much loss, so much difficulty.
And we're holding to, clinging tightly to the truth that that is not how you intended it to be.
And that Jesus is the linchpin and redeeming and restoring all of it back to your will and your way.
And so as we wait in the blurry middle, in the confusing middle, God, give us faith to see who you are.
Faith to see what you're doing behind the scenes.
And God, bring your kingdom on earth as it is in heaven.
In Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
I have this recurring daydream that usually pops into my head on long car rides when I'm trying to pass the time.
It goes something like this.
What would I do if I won the lottery?
Has anybody ever had similar daydreams?
I'm hopefully not alone in that.
Well, I want you to just do me a favor.
This is going to be probably the only time you'll ever hear me say this from stage.
Just for a few moments, ignore what I'm saying.
And I want you to drift into your own daydream.
Just for a second, what would you do if you won the lottery?
We could rephrase it.
What would you do if your work paid you the same salary they're paying you now to not come into work?
If you had just an excess of money or if you just had an excess of time, what would you do?
What about a position of power or influence?
Is there a position, a leadership position or a role that you dream about being in?
If you didn't have to do the work to get there, if somebody just magically plopped you in that role, which role would you select?
Now, I think this experiment will help us pinpoint exactly what we most value in our lives.
I read a quote as I was preparing for this message.
I've been chewing on it ever since.
It says,
Every choice a person makes is somehow guided by their search for ultimate fulfillment, for value.
We all have this idea of what we want our life to be, this value that we're placing in front of our lives.
And whether we realize it or not, directly or indirectly, every decision that we make, small and big, is aimed at achieving, accomplishing, grabbing hold of the thing that we ultimately value the most.
Whatever we, as individuals, define as ultimate value or the aim for our lives will trickle down to every decision we make.
And our two parables this morning today are aimed at that very question.
What Jesus wants us to wrestle with is what is the ultimate value in our life?
What is the thing that we are striving for with everything that we have?
Sometimes we might not fully realize it, but there is something that we have agreed to, believed that if we get it, it will give us the satisfaction and the value that we're looking for.
And Jesus wants us to wrestle with this question.
What is it?
And will it deliver the results that we think it will, that we're hoping it will?
And then ultimately, the backdoor question that Jesus is going to throw behind the window is what if there's something immensely more valuable available to you?
Would you be willing to consider it?
Would you be willing to set aside all your other values for something of utmost value?
That's the question we're going to wrestle with today.
And now is when I no longer give you permission to daydream, all right?
Daydreaming is over.
I need you to lock in.
It's time.
We're going to read our parables.
And what I want to do right now is I want to read these parables three times slowly before we start getting into the Bible.
The explanation and application of the text.
Because what we have to realize is that when the parables were taught, they weren't taught like a sermon.
They weren't taught and broken down in the moment.
They were given as a story to capture our imagination, as a story that we would take with us.
As the audience left Jesus, he wanted this story just going around in their minds and their hearts.
And so I want that experience for us just for a moment.
But we're Western, so I will explain it to the best of my ability after that.
But first, let's just get this into our hearts and our imaginations.
If you want to, close your eyes.
If that's something that would help you, it would help me.
But I have to read, so I can't.
Let's go ahead.
It's Matthew chapter 13, starting in verse 44.
When a man found it, he hid it again.
And then in his joy, he went and sold all that he had and he bought that field.
Again, the kingdom of heaven is like a merchant looking for fine pearls.
When he found one of great value, he went away and he sold everything he had and bought it.
The kingdom of heaven is like a treasure hidden in a field.
When a man found it, he hid it again.
And then in his joy, he went and sold all that he had and he bought that field.
Again, the kingdom of heaven is like a merchant looking for fine pearls.
When he found one of great value, he went away and sold everything that he had and bought it.
The kingdom of heaven is like a treasure hidden in a field.
When a man found it, he hid it again.
And then in his joy, he went and he sold all that he had and he bought the field.
Again, the kingdom of heaven is like a merchant looking for fine pearls.
When he found one of great value, he went away and he sold everything that he had and he bought it.
It's the word of the Lord.
You guys are getting better.
Thanks be to God.
We'll get there one day.
These two short, similar stories give a holistic picture of how the kingdom of heaven is to be seen and to be received by those that Jesus is announcing it to.
Last week, Corey gave us a really clear and short definition of what the kingdom of heaven is.
The kingdom of heaven, he said, is the rule and reign of God breaking into the world through Jesus.
This is the kingdom.
It's not primarily a message about where you go when you die or what value God can add to your life right now.
The kingdom of heaven is about submitting your life to a king who brings resurrection to this broken and dying world.
And we could add to that definition or adapt it a little bit for our message this week because our message is about receiving the kingdom.
I would say it this way.
The kingdom of heaven is an invitation to submit to the rule and reign of God breaking into the world through Jesus.
This is what we're being placed before us.
This is what Jesus is setting down before us.
It's an invitation to accept God's rule and his reign over our lives because we believe that he is bringing about redemption, that he is bringing in the reign of God through Jesus.
This is the invitation that Jesus offers.
And anybody that tells you any other invitation from Jesus is focusing on smaller elements of the invitation.
But this is the holistic invitation of Jesus, that the rule and reign of God is breaking into the world through Jesus, and you're invited to participate.
Now, in both of our stories, I see four primary activities that the participants of those uncovering the treasure of God's kingdom participate in.
And that's going to be the framework for the rest of our time together.
Four activities.
The first is finding.
If we look at the text, we can see that both individuals in these stories find the kingdom of heaven.
One is actively searching for it while the other seems to accidentally stumble upon it.
But they both find something of immense value.
Now, we don't know exactly why this man walking through a field is walking through a field.
He seems to be out for a nice afternoon stroll, relatively content with his life as it is.
So content with his life as it is that he's just nonchalantly trespassing on someone else's property.
He's just, he's so, like, content with the world that he's just like, oh, property lines, boundary lines.
Man made.
Who needs those?
And he stumbles upon a treasure in this field.
And to us, to our Western minds, this sounds insane.
Because we don't typically bury treasures, although my grandparents, I think, have some coffee cans somewhere that hopefully they wrote down where they're at.
This isn't a typical experience of us with banks, but this was a common experience for the people of this day.
They would have buried valuable treasures on their property.
And because there was so much turmoil at this time, because there was so much war, so many invasions, so much land being taken and stolen,
it would be common, somewhat common, for there to be treasure that someone doesn't know exists,
because the person who put it there is long gone or that land isn't in their possession anymore.
And so this seemingly content man on an afternoon stroll comes across a treasure that causes him to liquidate everything that he owns to buy the field and receive the lost treasure.
And we shouldn't get stuck on this morality question of whether or not he should have told the owner of the field that the treasure was there.
The owner didn't know the treasure was there, therefore it wasn't his treasure.
Totally legal in this day, fine, whatever.
You can wrestle with it all you want.
But all I'm saying is if I walk into Goodwill next week and there's a Scotty Cameron putter for sale for $5,
I'm not telling the owners of Goodwill what they have.
I'm just giving them the five bucks and walking away, right?
So this seemingly content man comes across a treasure that he wasn't looking for.
But the moment he comes across it, he's willing to liquidate everything he owns.
The merchant, on the other hand, is actively searching for a pearl of great value.
In this day, the pearl would have been the most valuable jewel.
For us, think diamond.
This is what they would have thought in their minds.
This is the most valuable jewel of the day.
And he spends his life, his job is actively looking for valuable pearls.
And he comes across one in his estimation that is the most valuable pearl that he will ever come across in the rest of his life.
If he were to continue to search from this day on until he dies, he thinks he will not find a pearl more valuable than this one.
And he sells everything he has to buy it.
And I think all of us in the room can resonate with one of these two characters on one level or another when it comes to our search for ultimate fulfillment, for value.
Maybe you're here and you're relatively chill.
You're relatively content with your life as it is.
You've got a decent life, a happy family.
Your daily needs are met.
You're a little stressed.
But all in all, you don't have much to complain about.
And you're not giving much thought beyond today.
You're not wrestling with the difficult questions of life and purpose.
Why are you here?
You're just like, yeah, life's good.
But others of us are like the merchant who we've been on a search for a long time, trying to figure out why we're here.
What is this life all about?
Why does it matter?
What value can I add?
What value can I receive?
We are searching, actively searching.
And maybe you've tried just about everything there is this world has to offer.
Maybe some things have worked better than others, but you still haven't found what you're looking for.
And I still haven't found what I'm looking for.
Thank you.
Whatever character you wrestled with most or whatever character you were most similar to before surrendering to Jesus,
I think that the reality is the next step for both of them is the same.
Whether they stumbled upon it or actively were looking for it, the second step is they saw the value in the treasure.
One person stumbled upon the value, one person was searching for it, but both immediately realized what they had when they found it.
It was something worth giving everything up for.
My hunch, as a pastor who does life with many of you, who regularly has conversations about deep meaning and value and purpose,
my hunch is this is the sticking point for many of us.
Whether you're actively following Jesus, whether you're a fan of his teachings, or whether you're a curious bystander just trying to figure out what he's all about,
the decision Jesus is confronting his audience with is, do you value the kingdom of heaven as the ultimate value in your life?
Even if it doesn't look like what you expected it to look like.
This is the surprising arrival element of the kingdom.
See, at this point in time, most of the Jews in Jesus' audience, they were anticipating God's kingdom to come.
They had prophecies about it.
They had an entire history of stories that were all leading up to the climax of God coming in and breaking Israel free from its oppression.
They were anticipating God's kingdom, but they were primarily anticipating it to come with power and to immediately benefit their physical lives.
They were expecting for God to show up in unimaginably clear ways and for him to bring about his kingdom once and for all.
But what Jesus was teaching about was the kingdom that they were expecting, but it was coming in a way that was different than they expected it.
He didn't roll the treasure into the city streets and open it up for everyone to see.
It's more like a treasure hidden in a field.
It comes in unexpected ways with upside down value systems.
It's a kingdom where the last are first, where true life is found through sacrificial love,
and where those who receive it, and this is what they were not expecting and did not know what to do with it,
that those who received the kingdom would be persecuted and even killed for it.
And yet, Jesus is saying, it is immeasurably more valuable than anything else you could build your life on.
Because the kingdom of heaven is an unstoppable force that overcomes the power of sin and darkness
and will provide the recipient with abundant life now, no matter your circumstances,
and eternal life in the future.
It's like a mustard seed planted in the ground.
And the plant overcomes everything.
It's small.
It's seemingly insignificant.
But it is unstoppable.
This is what Jesus is saying the kingdom of heaven is like.
And he's inviting his audience to decide whether or not they will value it the way that he is valuing it.
He's placing it on the table and saying, this kingdom that I'm preaching about is worth more than anything else you could ever pursue.
And he's giving us the option to consider it and to choose.
And many of the people in the audience would say, this is not what I thought the kingdom of heaven was.
This is not what I was expecting.
I'm out.
But these two characters in our parables, they see the value.
And the question then for us becomes, do we truly understand what the kingdom of heaven is?
The kingdom of heaven that Jesus brings?
Because there's plenty of redefinitions available to us today.
There's plenty of people that come in the name of Jesus, that come under the banner of the kingdom of heaven,
and will offer you all kinds of things.
But what is the kingdom that Jesus promises?
And what does it require of us?
And do we understand the kingdom as it's offered by Jesus and not some repackaging that makes it easier and more simple for us to grab a hold of?
Maybe something that we can put in our pocket.
Something that we have to give up Sunday morning for.
This is not the kingdom that Jesus comes to bring.
The kingdom that Jesus comes to bring infiltrates every aspect of your life.
Changes your entire value system upside down.
Do we truly understand the kingdom that Jesus comes to offer?
And do we see it as more valuable than anything else this world has to offer?
And I'll be honest with you.
It looks foolish to the world.
But to us who are being saved, it is the very power of God for salvation.
The kingdom is not a virtuous add-on.
It's not something we leverage for our own personal gain.
It's not a morality we embrace to make us feel righteous.
It's not a self-help framework that gives us a well-rounded life.
And this, I'm afraid, is what many in the church in America view the kingdom as.
It's a nice thing to add on to our lives.
It's hope for the future.
It's something that makes us feel a little better about ourselves when we go to sleep at night.
But that's not the kingdom that Jesus is offering.
He's offering a kingdom of total surrender, of laying down everything else you value in your life, and letting God's values dictate everything that you do.
It's not easy.
It's not comfortable.
But it's worth it.
I love how Tim Keller says it.
He says, religious people find God useful.
But kingdom people find God beautiful.
And how often do we redefine the kingdom in a way something that we can use for our own benefit, for our own gain, something that we can add to our lives to leverage our own status, our own worth, our own value.
And the kingdom that Jesus offers us is far more beautiful than that.
It's one that with joy we can be willing to lay down every other pursuit of our life in order to pursue this one thing, this thing that sacrifices our own desires for the sake of others, to love God with our whole heart, mind, soul, and strength, and to love our neighbor as ourself.
Both the merchant and the man in the field immediately realize the treasure is worth the sacrifice.
And the third activity they do is they give up everything.
With joy, they sell everything they have, everything they've ever placed their value in, to get the one thing that matters more than anything else.
To take some words from Jesus, the one thing that rust won't erode, that moss can't destroy, that thieves cannot break in and steal.
The kingdom of heaven cannot be taken from us.
No difficult circumstance, no amount of time, no aging, no loss of income, nothing can take us.
Nothing can take the kingdom of heaven from us.
This is why Paul in Philippians 3, the verse that we read at worship, he says,
It's everything else I consider rubbish, garbage, it's not worth anything because it will be taken away from me in an instant.
All of the new gadgets and toys that we are searching after, that we are saving up for.
I heard one pastor say, it is the yard sale of two years from now.
Everything that you are chasing after, everything that you think will add value to your life, is going to end up in a dump somewhere.
But the kingdom of heaven is worth the sacrifice.
Comfort, pleasure, success, status, and significance, all of these things we chase after, all of these values we place before ourselves,
they're all fleeting and they're outside of our control.
No matter how self-determined, how strong-willed you think you are, no matter how good you have been at accomplishing the goals you set before yourself up until this day,
you are not in control of everything.
There are too many circumstances outside of your control that can break in and that can rob and that can steal and that can take from you in an instant.
And if you don't believe me, do me a favor and read the book of Ecclesiastes this week.
King Solomon, who has more wealth, more status, more comfort, more power, and more pleasure than all of us in the room combined times a lot.
He writes a book at the height of his powers.
When the nation of Israel is so powerful, so wealthy, so prosperous, when he's got all of the food, all of the women, all of the everything that he could ever want or imagine,
he writes a book and the opening line goes something like this,
all the works under the sun are vanity, like grabbing at the wind.
I'll admit, it's a depressing book, if you take it at face value.
But there's an underlying thesis behind everything that Solomon says in the book of Ecclesiastes,
and that thesis is, there is more to life than what's under the sun.
There is more to life than what we see on earth.
And then a descendant of Solomon by the name of Jesus comes along, and he says,
the kingdom of heaven is like a secure treasure worth giving up everything in pursuit of.
See how these two stories work together?
Jesus is saying, I know that you're pursuing comfort, pleasure, status, success, wealth,
whatever the thing is that you thought of when I asked you to stop ignoring what I had to say,
whatever that thing is, whatever that pursuit is,
even if it's not necessarily sinful, there's plenty of good and meaningful and good to society things that we pursue.
But if we pursue them as ultimate, if we're looking to find our satisfaction in them, it will fall short.
We will be left hungry.
We will be left thirsty.
But there's something beyond the things of this earth.
There's a kingdom that's worth sacrificing everything for.
And our characters, they give up everything to receive this treasure.
That's the last action.
They receive it.
But what exactly is this treasure that they have received?
What are they giving up everything for?
Now, hopefully we've unpacked this a little bit,
but the question becomes, what is it that they receive?
Easy.
They get to go to heaven when they die.
Come on, people.
Seriously?
That was a test and you all failed.
I just preached this entire sermon.
And then I go back to the thing that you're used to hearing.
It's all about going to heaven when you die.
And you guys just, you were cool.
You were content.
Nobody was going to stand up and yell heresy.
Eternal life is part of the package, but it's so much more than that.
It's freedom from our slavery to sin.
It's abundant life now.
It's peace that passes understanding in the worst circumstances of your life.
It's the indwelling presence of the Holy Spirit that guides you, comforts you, prays for you,
and transforms you into a person characterized by love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness,
faithfulness, gentleness, and self-control.
It's living on earth like the rule and reign of heaven is here now and is awaiting its full realization.
And I am preaching better than you all are listening.
I almost ran out of breath there.
For my millennials, for my Gen Xers, the kingdom of heaven is like being red-pilled.
It's waking up to the reality that living for any other value might be easier and more comfortable,
but it's actually slavery and death.
There's plenty of pursuits that are easy and comfortable and that will be valuable to our lives,
but in the end, it's slavery and it's death.
But the offer of the kingdom of heaven is freedom and life.
It's being activated to live on mission with God and reconciling this broken world back to life.
It's an invitation that is available to everyone, but will be ignored by many.
And those who reject it will laugh at those who accept it.
They'll think we're foolish.
Main point.
If you don't remember anything else, I say today, remember this.
The kingdom of heaven is a free gift with ultimate value that requires sacrificial acceptance.
The kingdom of heaven, it's free, it's a gift, it's offered to anyone who would take it.
And it's more valuable than anything else you could pursue, accomplish, achieve, or receive.
But in order to pick it up, it requires sacrificial acceptance.
Now, some of you might protest.
But Ryan, this sounds an awful lot like worship-based salvation.
Right?
Aren't we Protestant?
Don't we believe in grace by faith alone, in Christ alone?
What happened to this message that I've heard my whole life?
Are you saying that if we want to be a citizen of God's kingdom, we have to work our way in or buy our way in?
I do have a few packages to offer.
I'm just kidding.
I couldn't even say that one with a straight face.
No, of course not.
Salvation is a free gift.
But it's a gift that when proclaimed, when Jesus proclaims the kingdom, when the apostles proclaim the kingdom, they say that if you want to be a citizen of the kingdom, you have to repent and believe.
Repentance is turning around.
It's setting aside what you previously held as most ultimate, as most valuable.
And belief or faith, as the New Testament language continues, it's a new allegion.
It's picking something else up as the ultimate value of your lives.
Eric, do you mind coming up here?
Sweet.
Thank you.
I didn't tell him this was happening.
Huh?
You have a sword?
Yeah, bring the sword.
No, I'm kidding.
I wanted to just illustrate how I think this often works in our lives a little bit.
And Eric is strong.
So I figured I was going to pick your wife because she has long arms, like a wide wingspan.
But I think I'm choosing you instead.
It's Mother's Day.
I didn't want to embarrass her.
All right, let's, I'm going to take a guess at what I think Eric might find as ultimate value in his life.
I know it's, I know it's, I know it's not comfort or pleasure because I, I've gone to eat with Eric and if pleasure or comfort was your God, you would eat more tasty foods.
He's like looking on the package to see what kind of oil things are made with.
Like that's, so comfort and pleasure, not your thing.
I'm going to, I'm, I'm just going to give you significance.
I don't know if that's true or not, but can you?
Amen.
Proof, yeah.
Hey, hey, I got it right.
That's awesome.
All right.
So Eric is holding on to significance.
It is his ultimate aim in life.
Your ultimate value, the thing that you are pursuing with everything that you have.
Now I know, because we're friends, we talk.
You love God's kingdom.
Jesus comes in.
He invites you to participate in his kingdom.
He says the kingdom of heaven is like a treasure in a field.
Something worth giving everything up for, a pearl of great price that is worth selling everything for to buy.
And he offers you the kingdom of heaven.
It's a free gift.
Invitation is yours.
Would you, would you want to pick up the kingdom of heaven?
Don't ruin it.
Okay.
You got both for now.
How long do you think?
Yeah.
How long do you think you can hold both?
All right.
Which one do you want?
Oh, in theory?
Yeah.
This one.
All right.
Well, then put that one down.
Feels good though.
All right.
So you have picked up the kingdom of heaven.
How is that?
That is pretty awkward.
Pretty hard to.
You have received the kingdom of heaven as your ultimate value.
Now, time's gone on.
Living for God is pretty good.
But you remember what chasing success was like?
You want to, you want to put that down at all?
You want, maybe you want to, you want to try both again?
Yeah.
What do you got?
How about that?
This is working out better than I thought it was going to.
Is that, is that comfortable?
Is that easy?
Does that sound like a, does that sound like my yoke is easy and my burden is light?
Okay.
Which one do you want to set down?
Period.
I'm in church.
I have to.
That is the right answer.
All right.
Thank you, Eric.
I think this is how the invitation works.
It's free and it's better and it's longer lasting and it's worthy of giving up everything.
But we so often think that we can just have, have it all.
I think that we can chase after both things at the same time.
The problem is the value systems are totally competing.
And I think Eric did a great job of showing how much of our life works as Christians, that like we get these, we come into these seasons where we just, we're loving on the Lord and we want to serve him.
We want to follow him.
We want to obey him.
We pick up the kingdom of heaven and then something happens.
Difficulty comes in our life.
It doesn't pan out the way that we thought it would.
We're sacrificing, loving, serving, and it's not filling us the way that we thought it would.
And we go back to whatever it is that we pursued in the past.
And we try and do both at the same time.
And what Jesus is offering to us is a kingdom that is of ultimate worth, of ultimate value.
But it is got to be the only thing in our hands if we're going to do it right.
And the reality is, like, I don't want, like, reality is it's not that picking up the kingdom of heaven means you won't get any of these other things.
It just means that they won't be the ultimate value in your life.
I love how Paul puts it in Philippians chapter 4.
If you don't go to church, this is probably the one verse that you know.
Not the first one, but the second one.
He says this in Philippians 4.12.
I know how to live on almost nothing or with everything.
I have learned the secret of living in every situation, whether with a full stomach or with empty, with plenty or with little.
For I can do everything through Christ who gives me strength.
Paul says, I picked up the kingdom of heaven.
And there were times when I was, everything was great.
I was successful.
I was comfortable.
I had a full stomach.
Life was good.
And then there were times when I didn't have any of this.
And he said, at the end of the day, I still was convinced that holding on to the kingdom of heaven was more valuable than putting it down to get one of these.
I can do anything through Christ who strengthens me is not about winning a football game.
It's about contentment with holding on to the kingdom alone, no matter what else comes with it.
Picking up the kingdom does not mean we won't experience any of these other things.
It just means our life won't be crushed if we don't.
And our satisfaction won't be in them if we do.
And there's a man by the name of A.W. Tozer who said what I just said, but said it way better.
So let's read that.
He says, the man who has God for his treasure has all things in one.
Many ordinary treasures may be denied him.
Or if he is allowed to have them, the enjoyment of them will be so tempered that they will never be necessary to his happiness.
Or if he must see them go one after one, he will scarcely feel a sense of loss.
For having the source of all things, he has in one all satisfaction, all pleasure, all delight.
Whatever he may lose, he has actually lost nothing.
For he now has it all in one.
And he has it purely, legitimately, and forever.
Have you found your ultimate value in God's kingdom?
Have you seen it as a treasure that's worth giving everything up for?
And what might you still be trying to pick up?
What might you try to be two-handed as you go along?
It's not as easy as it looks.
I'm stronger than Eric, apparently.
I'm just kidding.
Hey, my coach is over here, all right?
She knows.
She built these muscles.
Thank you, by the way.
I appreciate that.
What is it?
First of all, the question is, have you embraced the kingdom of heaven as your ultimate value?
Amen.
This is the question that Jesus is confronting us with.
And he knows that he's going to offer this invitation, and some of you are going to say no.
But that is not his desire.
That is not my desire.
That is not our desire as a church.
We want everyone to accept this invitation.
But maybe you've accepted this invitation, and you're in a season where you're still trying to carry both at the same time.
It's exhausting.
And it's not true pursuit of God's kingdom.
So where are you at?
What might God be inviting you to this morning?
Maybe you've made this decision, and you haven't been baptized yet.
We've got a baptism coming up on June 1st.
Baptism is this public declaration of allegiance to the kingdom of heaven, first and foremost.
Not that anything else won't come or go, but the kingdom is my ultimate allegiance.
It is the value I am pursuing.
If I won the lottery, the way in which I would invest the money would demonstrate that I have a priority towards God's kingdom.
Maybe you need to take that step and get baptized.
Maybe you need to do some business with God, some of these things that you're holding on to.
As we begin to land the plane, I want to bring up one more thing.
I'm going to do it really fast, because we're running late.
Throughout church history, these parables, these two short, simple parables, in classic church fashion, have been disagreed upon on how to interpret.
That never happens in church, right?
There have been two primary ways to interpret these parables, and although I think the approach we took this morning is the approach that Jesus intended, the other one is equally true and beautiful.
In that interpretation, they see the merchant chasing after the pearl as Jesus, searching for you and for me.
Jesus says, I came to seek and save the lost.
Giving up everything so that he could have us.
You are so valued by God that he sent his one and only son to die for you, to purchase your way into his family, so that he might receive you.
Titus says, we are God's very own possession, those of us who have embraced the kingdom of God.
I was listening to a podcast this week, a Jewish scholar who teaches the New Testament, which is a really interesting thing to do.
And this guy was asking her, as she studied the New Testament from a Jewish perspective from her entire life, he said, what is the thing that you've found most intriguing or beautiful about Jesus?
And she stumbled around the question for a bit, trying to figure out exactly what she wanted to say, saying that there's a lot she couldn't pick.
And then she landed on this one.
She said, as far as I can tell, Jesus does not ask his followers to do something that he won't do himself.
Yes, Jesus is inviting you to lay down everything else that you're pursuing, to take hold of his kingdom.
But it's not something he's unwilling to do himself.
As a matter of fact, he goes before us.
He sets the example for us.
He laid down his life so that we could have one.
And he invites us to do the same.
He invites us to lay down our lives so that others might have life in him.
And there's nothing more valuable than building a kingdom that will last forever.
I asked the team to come up and lead in a hymn that most of you are probably familiar with, Turn Your Eyes Upon Jesus.
And I just, I've been, as I've been preparing for this message, this line has been going around in my head over and over again.
And this is my prayer for you.
And this is my prayer for me.
The line goes, and the things of this earth will go strangely dim.
May this be true of us, church.
So are you weary and troubled?
No light in the darkness you see.
There's life for a look at the Savior.
And life more abundant and free.
Sing with me, church.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Look full in his wonderful faith.
And the things of earth will grow strangely dim.
In the lives is glory and grace.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus again.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Look full in his wonderful faith.
And the things of earth will grow strangely dim.
In the light of his glory and grace.
One more time, church.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Of all in his wonderful faith.
And the things of earth will grow strangely dim.
In the light of his glory and grace.
And the things.
And the things of earth will grow strangely dim.
In the light of his glory and grace.
My prayer, church, for each of us.
We need to be a people that learn to value the kingdom of heaven so much that everything else in this world fades.
I'm going to dismiss.
There should be some volunteers at the prayer team.
If there's anything you want to talk about or need prayer for.
We'd love to have you stick around.
If not, I'm going to send you out in peace.
And hopefully you can beat the Catholics to the Mother's Day lunch places first.
They got a new pope.
They're happy.
They can wait in line.
All right?
I'm going to get in trouble for that one.
Go and teach church.
We love you.
I'm going to get in trouble for that one.
I'm going to take in trouble for that one.